VILIUS DZEMYDA

Front-End Web Developer

PROFILE

Strong technical and communication skills. More than six years of experience in building and maintaining client-side web applications. Good understanding of UI design patterns, user experience, technology stacks, development tools, and best practices. Open-minded, analytical, logical, able to grasp difficult concepts and good at troubleshooting.

EDUCATION

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development - (Feb 2019 – Present)

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, GitHub, Data management,

Agile development, Frameworks

School of Technology and Business - Veisiejai, Lithuania

Leaving Certificate - (Jun 2004)

English, IT, Arts, Maths, Physics

SKILLS

Problem Solving, Communication Website Development, SEO Prototyping, UI Design Responsive Web Design

TECH

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js Bulma, Bootstrap, SCSS Linux, CLI, Git, npm, Webpack WordPress, Nuxt.js Netlify, Cloudways

EXPERIENCE

(Jan 2017 – Present)

Freelance

Navan, Ireland

(Apr 2015 – Nov 2015)

Purple Pod

Navan, Ireland

(Jun 2011 – Feb 2014)

The DG Group / Snap Dunshaughlin, Ireland

Web Developer

Plan, design and develop WordPress sites. Setup domains and emails, migrate and backup data, configure servers. Support clients by phone and email. Design and develop Vue.js static sites and deploy to Netlify.

Front-End Developer

Convert multiple design mock-ups into fully functional templates for an online store. Responsible for the design and development of WordPress sites, and daily website maintenance.

Web Developer

My primary task was to convert Photoshop mock-ups into fully functional websites. To prototype faster and save time, I built an in-house CSS framework and starter WordPress theme. I made old websites mobile-friendly, implemented responsive techniques, and tested for browser compatibility. Support clients by email.